<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Recipes</string>
    <string name="label">Indian Food Recipes</string>
    <string name="spinnerLabel">Choose a dish :</string>
    <string name="buttonLabel">Go to Recipe</string>
    <string name="backBtnLabel">Go to Choices</string>
    <string-array name="RecipeNames">
        <item>Chicken Dum Biryani</item>
        <item>Chicken Fry</item>
        <item>Mysore Bonda</item>
        <item>Pani Puri</item>
        <item>Payasam</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="RecipeDesc">
        <item>Chicken Biryani is the most ordered and liked rice preparation in India. Here is an easy chicken biryani recipe. North or south Indian chicken biryani has its own regional recipes.\n\nIngredients:\n\n\t\u2022 2 cups Basmati Rice\n\t\u2022 3/4 kg Chicken Pieces\n\t\u2022 1 cup beaten Yogurt (curd)\n\t\u2022 3 sliced onion\n\t\u2022 1 medium Tomato chopped 1/2 cup Tomato Puree\n\t\u2022 2 tsp Red Chilli Powder\n\t\u2022 1 tsp Turmeric Powder\n\t\u2022 1 tsp Roasted cumin powder\n\t\u2022 2 tsp Garam Masala Powder\n\t\u2022 1/2 tsp Green Cardamom Powder\n\t\u2022 1 tsp Coriander Powder\n\t\u2022 1/2 cup Warm Milk\n\t\u2022 Saffron a pinch\n\t\u2022 Salt to taste\n\t\u2022 7 tbsp Ghee / Oil Grind to Paste: 1 tsp Ginger Paste\n\t\u2022 1/2 tsp Garlic Paste\n\t\u2022 1/4 cup Coriander Leaves\n\t\u2022 1/4 cup Mint Leaves\n\t\u2022 3 -4 Green Chillies\n\t\u2022 For garnish 2 tbsp Green Coriander Leaves\n\t\u2022 2 tblsp Mint Leaves (Pudina)\n\nHow to make easy chicken biryani :\n\n\t\u2022 First make a fine paste of all the ingredients under the Grind to paste using a tablespoon of water.\n\t\u2022 Mix tomato puree, yogurt, green paste made earlier, red chilli powder, turmeric powder, roasted cumin powder, garam masala, coriander powder and salt. Stir well.\n\t\u2022 Marinate the chicken with this mixture and keep aside for 3-4 hours in refrigerator.\n\t\u2022 Heat oil in a pan. Fry the onions until golden brown.\n\t\u2022 In a small bowl take the warm milk and soak the saffron in it and keep aside.\n\t\u2022 Add the marinated chicken and cook for 10 minutes. Stir occasionally.\n\t\u2022 Now add the beaten curd and chopped tomato and cook further till the oil separates.\n\t\u2022 Check the salt at this stage as later you cannot add the salt.\n\t\u2022 Now add the rice and mix well with soft hand as not to break the rice grains.\n\t\u2022 Add 4 cups of water to the rice. Mix saffron in milk and add to it.\n\t\u2022 Add cardamom powder. Stir once.\n\t\u2022 Cover the lid and cook on low flame till the rice is done.\n\t\u2022 Take it out on a rice platter.\n\t\u2022 Garnish with green coriander and mint leaves and serve hot.\n\t\u2022 This chicken biryani goes well with mix vegetable raita.</item>
        <item>Ingredients :-\n\n\t\u2022 1 pound chicken breast or thigh, skinned, legs divided into thighs and drumsticks, breasts split in half\n\t\u2022 1 tablespoon juice from about 1 lime\n\t\u2022 Kosher salt\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon ground black pepper\n\t\u2022 1 1/2 tablespoons grated ginger, divided\n\t\u2022 2 tablespoons grated garlic, divided\n\t\u2022 1 tablespoon whole black peppercorns (or less to taste)\n\t\u2022 2 tablespoons coconut, vegetable, or canola oil\n\t\u2022 1 medium onion sliced thinly (about 1 cup)\n\t\u2022 2 small green chillis slit lengthwise\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon ground fennel\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon ground cumin\n\t\u2022 1/2 teaspoon turmeric powder\n\t\u2022 10 curry leaves\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon soy sauce\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon sugar\n\t\u2022 1 large tomato split in half lengthwise\n\t\u2022 1/2 cup water\n\nDirections :- \n\n\t1. Combine chicken, lime juice, 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt, ground black pepper, 1 tablespoon ginger, and 1 tablespoon garlic in a large bowl and toss to coat. Transfer to a plastic bag, refrigerate, and let marinate for at least 30 minutes and up to overnight.\n\n\t2. Grind the whole peppercorns in the mortar and pestle until roughly ground. Heat oil in a heavy-bottomed saucepan over medium heat until shimmering. Add onion, remaining 1/2 tablespoon ginger, remaining tablespoon garlic, and chillis and cook, stirring, until fragrant, taking care not to brown the onions, about 5 minutes total. Reduce heat to low. Add fennel powder, cumin powder, turmeric, and curry leaves. Stir vigorously until fragrant, about 2 minutes. Increase heat to medium. Add soy sauce, sugar, tomatoes and the marinated chicken. Fry the chicken in this flavoured oil until browned, about 10 minutes, scraping the bottom of the pan if anything sticks.\n\n\t3. Add water and cover. Allow the dish to cook for 10 minutes covered, Then remove the lid, increase heat to high and stir around till water has dried up totally, about 5 minutes. Season to taste with salt. Serve hot with rotis, dosas or with bread.</item>
        <item>Ingredients :- \n\n\t\u2022 1 Cup All Purpose Flour\n\t\u2022 1 Cup Curd\n\t\u2022 3 Tablespoons Rice Flour\n\t\u2022 1 Teaspoon Salt\n\t\u2022 1/4 Tablespoons Baking Soda\n\t\u2022 1 Teaspoon Chopped Green Chillies\n\t\u2022 1 Teaspoon Chopped Ginger\n\t\u2022 1/2 Teaspoon Cumin Seeds\n\nDirections :- \n\n\t\u2022 Take 1 cup all purpose flour in a bowl.\n\t\u2022 Add 3 tablespoons rice flour.\n\t\u2022 Add 1 teaspoon salt or salt to taste.\n\t\u2022 Add 1/4 teaspoon baking soda, 1/2 teaspoon cumin seeds, 1 teaspoon chopped.\n\t\u2022 ginger, 1 teaspoon chopped green chillies and mix.\n\t\u2022 For 1 cup all purpose flour, add 1 cup curd.\n\t\u2022 Add water and mix.\n\t\u2022 The shape of the bajji depends on the consistency of the batter.\n\t\u2022 If the batter is too thin, the bajjis won\'t be round.\n\t\u2022 Let it sit for 20 minutes at least.\n\t\u2022 Wet your hands and mix the batter.\n\t\u2022 For making the bondas, wet your hands and drop the batter slowly.\n\t\u2022 Heat oil sufficient for deep fry.\n\t\u2022 Wet your hands and drop the batter into the oil.\n\t\u2022 The stove should be on medium flame.\n\t\u2022 Flip after a couple of minutes.\n\t\u2022 Flip and fry till they turn brown.\n\t\u2022 Mysore bajjis are ready now.\n\t\u2022 Serve with favourite chutney or sambar.\n\nMysore bonda is one of the popular snacks served in tiffin centres in India.</item>
        <item>Ingredients :-\n\nFilling:\n\t\u2022 1 cup dry green or yellow peas, picked through\n\t\u2022 1/2 teaspoon ground turmeric\n\t\u2022 1/4 teaspoon baking soda \n\t\u2022 Salt and ground black pepper\n\t\u2022 Red chili powder\n\t\u2022 1/4 cup fresh chopped cilantro\n\t\u2022 1 large potato, boiled, peeled and cubed\n\t\u2022 Chaat masala\n\t\u2022 3 teaspoons lemon juice\n\t\u2022 1 tablespoon tamarind concentrate \n\t\u2022 2 teaspoons chaat masala (spice mixture of toasted cumin, black pepper, dried mango and red chili powder)\n\nPani (Spiced Water):\n\t\u2022 2 teaspoons sugar\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon roasted cumin powder\n\t\u2022 1 teaspoon dry mint powder\n\t\u2022 Red chili powder, for sprinkling\n\t\u2022 Salt, for sprinkling\n\nPuri:\n\t\u2022 1 cup sooji (semolina flour)\n\t\u2022 1/4 cup whole-wheat flour\n\t\u2022 1/4 teaspoon salt\n\t\u2022 Corn or vegetable oil, for frying\n\nDirections :- \n\nFor the filling:\n\t\u2022 Soak the peas in water overnight, and then drain.\n\t\u2022 Put the peas in a pot with the turmeric and baking soda and add enough water to just cover the peas.\n\t\u2022 Bring the mixture to a boil, and then reduce to a simmer and cook until the peas are soft.\n\t\u2022 Sprinkle with salt, black pepper and red chili powder.\n\t\u2022 Let the peas cool to room temperature.\n\t\u2022 Mix the peas with the cilantro and potatoes and a generous amount of chaat masala in a bowl.\n\t\u2022 Your filling is ready. \n\nFor the pani:\n\t\u2022 Mix the lemon juice, tamarind, masala, sugar, cumin powder, mint powder, sprinkle of chili powder and salt in a bowl with 4 cups tap water.\n\t\u2022 Pour the pani into a glass jar and refrigerate. \n\nFor the puri:\n\t\u2022 Mix together the sooji, wheat flour and salt in a bowl.\n\t\u2022 Add enough water to make a soft dough.\n\t\u2022 Cover and let it sit for about 30 minutes.\n\t\u2022 Meanwhile, pour 1 inch of oil into a large deep skillet or wok.\n\t\u2022 Heat the oil over medium heat until a deep-fry thermometer registers 350 degrees F.\n\t\u2022 Roll the dough into approximately 1 1/4-inch-diameter discs.\n\t\u2022 Slip the discs into the hot oil one at a time, working in batches, flipping them with a slotted spoon as they puff up until light brown.\n\t\u2022 Drain on a paper-towel-lined-tray and let cool.\n\t\u2022 They will continue to crisp as they cool. \n\nTo serve :\n\t\u2022 put 6 to 8 puris on each plate with separate bowls of filling and pani on the side.\n\t\u2022 Provide a small spoon.\n\t\u2022 Lightly tap the top of a puri with the tip of the spoon handle to break and make a small hole wide enough to fill it.\n\t\u2022 Fill the puri halfway with some filling, then spoon the pani into it and pop it into your mouth.\n\t\u2022 Repeat with the remaining puri, filling and pani. \n\t\u2022 Enjoy the delicacy of the pani puri.</item>
        <item>Ingredients :- \n\n\t\u2022 0.74 tbsp green gram (dried mung beans)\n\t\u2022 1 tablespoon ghee, plus 1 tablespoon extra\n\t\u2022 200 g (7 oz/1 cup) sago (payasam)\n\t\u2022 30 g (1 oz) dried seviyan vermicelli noodles\n\t\u2022 2 tablespoons roughly chopped raw cashew nuts\n\t\u2022 1 tablespoon raisins\n\t\u2022 1 pinch of salt\n\t\u2022 875 ml (30 fl oz/3½ cups) coconut milk\n\t\u2022 200 g caster sugar\n\t\u2022 1 tsp ground cardamom\n\t\u2022 125 ml (4 fl oz/½ cup) coconut cream\n\nDirections :-\n\n\t1. Dry-roast the green gram in a heavy-based frying pan over medium heat for 4 minutes. Remove and set aside to cool slightly. Using a mortar and pestle (or spice grinder), pound the green gram into a fine powder. Set aside.\n\n\t2. Melt the ghee in the frying pan and fry the sago over medium heat for 3 minutes, or until it starts to puff and pop. Add the vermicelli noodles and fry for 1 minute, or until golden brown, stirring continuously so the vermicelli doesn’t burn. Remove and set aside. Fry the cashews and raisins in the extra ghee over low heat for 1–2 minutes until golden, then remove with a slotted spoon and drain on paper towel.\n\n\t3. Bring 875 ml (30 fl oz/3½ cups) water to the boil in a large saucepan. Add a pinch of salt, then quickly add the sago and vermicelli and stir well. Simmer for 18 minutes over low–medium heat, stirring regularly, until it thickens and the sago is cooked and turns transparent (stir continuously for the last 5 minutes so the sago doesn’t catch on the bottom of the pan). Add a little more water if needed.\n\n\t4. Add the coconut milk, bring almost to the boil, then reduce the heat to low and simmer for 3 minutes, stirring continuously, until the mixture starts to thicken slightly. Stir in the green gram powder and simmer for 3–4 minutes. Add the sugar, cardamom and coconut cream and cook for 4–5 minutes, stirring, until the mixture thickens a little. Stir in the fried cashews and raisins or sprinkle them on top. Serve hot in small cups.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
